<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Dmitry Popov</title>
    <link>http://dmipopov.github.io/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Dmitry Popov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 16:23:44 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dmipopov.github.io/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Deploying High Available Applications in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://dmipopov.github.io/posts/best-practices-for-deploying-high-available-applications-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 16:23:44 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dmipopov.github.io/posts/best-practices-for-deploying-high-available-applications-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult to deploy an application in Kubernetes with minimal working configuration. But when you want to provide your application with maximum availability and reliability, you will inevitably encounter a considerable number of pitfalls. In this article, I tried to systematize and describe the most important rules for deploying highly available applications in Kubernetes.
Functionality that is not available in Kubernetes &amp;ldquo;out of the box&amp;rdquo; will hardly be affected here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hide Kubernetes secrets with helm-secrets, sops and vals</title>
      <link>http://dmipopov.github.io/posts/hide_kubernetes_secrets_with_helm_secrets_sops_and_vals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 22:15:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dmipopov.github.io/posts/hide_kubernetes_secrets_with_helm_secrets_sops_and_vals/</guid>
      <description>Methods of secrets delivery Secrets need to be somehow delivered to Kubernetes clusters. There are two different approaches for this: pull and push.
Pull Secrets are delivered to clusters after deployment. For instance, if we use Helm Charts, we can specify metadata instead of the secret value.
We do not add secret values to the manifests at all, but specify only metadata. Secrets are created based on this metadata and downloaded from external storage &amp;ndash; for example, Hashicorp Vault.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
